<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <Baseliner.label>표준인</Baseliner.label>
  <Baseliner.description>커다란 유전적 변형 없이 자연적으로 진화한 인간.</Baseliner.description>
  
  <Dirtmole.label>더트몰</Dirtmole.label>
  <Dirtmole.description>With gray skin adapted to artificial light, they thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are extremely capable at digging or mining tasks. In the open, however, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance.\n\nAfter the first tunnel colonies failed due to the stress of confinement, colonization agencies began genetically altering colonists to live without open space or sunlight. This xenotype are known colloquially as dirtmoles. Today, dirtmoles have expanded out of their original tunnel homes and rule many confined spaces in the anthrosphere. They can be found in deep mines, cramped low-tech spacecraft, and teeming by the billions in the dark underlayers of countless urbworlds.</Dirtmole.description>
  <Dirtmole.descriptionShort>인공 조명에 적응한 회색 피부의 더트몰은 전투와 이동이 짧은 거리엥서 이루어지는 좁고 어두운 지역에서 살아왔습니다. 그들은 채굴과 복잡한 지하구조물을 탐색하는데 천부적입니다. 지상에서 이들은 광민감성으로 고통받으며 느리고 심한 근시를 가지고 있습니다.</Dirtmole.descriptionShort>
  
  <Genie.label>지니</Genie.label>
  <Genie.description>Designed to be engineers, genies' delicate bones and natural aptitude with machines allow them to manipulate devices with remarkable precision. They are emotionally cold and can follow orders where others might panic. However, they are fragile, and their amplified nerve impulses make them easy to debilitate with relatively little pain. With so much of their brains dedicated to analyzing machines, they lack the neural hardware to analyze emotions, so they sometimes come off as socially inept. Their dead calm makes it even harder for them to relate to what they see as madly-hotheaded baseliner humans.\n\nGenies were engineered thousands of years ago by a long-disbanded space navy to hold engineering positions on large starships. Today, genies still serve as engineers in great cities and fleets, but many can also be found working as lawyers, pilots, and musicians.</Genie.description>
  <Genie.descriptionShort>Designed to be engineers, genies have natural aptitude with machines, and are emotionally cold and calm. They are also fragile and vulnerable to pain. Focused on machines, they often come off as socially inept.</Genie.descriptionShort>
  
  <Highmate.label>하이메이트</Highmate.label>
  <Highmate.description>Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.\n\nOn a few wealthy worlds, highmate xenogerms are commercially available and some people become highmates as a sort of career. However, many societies find them abhorrent, either because they distract people from forming natural families, or because they are humans shaped to serve the pleasures of another. On such worlds they are either reserved as playthings of the powerful, or banned entirely. This particular line of highmate fits the fashions of classical Novaroma, but many other variants exist.</Highmate.description>
  <Highmate.descriptionShort>Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.</Highmate.descriptionShort>
  
  <Hussar.label>후사르</Hussar.label>
  <Hussar.description>Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice, which also makes them less likely to rebel against their commanders.\n\nWhile hussars' emotions make them dangerous in combat, they can't relate to baseliner humans. They are famous for their blood-red eyes and "hussar stare", a dead expression that unsettles many people. Their lack of expression and burning aggressive nature has led to many violent misunderstandings.\n\nIn most societies where they live, hussars are kept separated from the rest of the population. Hussars are single-purpose tools - and they generally aren't bothered by the fact.</Hussar.description>
  <Hussar.descriptionShort>Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice.</Hussar.descriptionShort>
  
  <Impid.label>임프</Impid.label>
  <Impid.description>Made for desert life, impid cultures live on many rimworlds and dry deathworlds. Impids are extremely fast-moving, easily tolerate high temperatures, and can spew fire from their mouths. Though they are masters on the sand, impids struggle in other environments. They are terrible with farming. They fight well at range, but in close combat their physical weakness becomes apparent.\n\nOutlanders call them dustrunners because of their speed over open terrain and resistance to heat. Some tribes call them devils because of their horns and because they burn their enemies. Impid tribes' combat tactics usually center on rapid-approach incendiary attacks using both handheld fire weapons and their fire spew ability.</Impid.description>
  <Impid.descriptionShort>Made for desert life, impids are very fast, can spew fire from their mouths, and easily tolerate high temperatures. They fight well at range, but in close combat they do little damage. They are terrible with farming, and have weak immune systems.</Impid.descriptionShort>
  
  <Neanderthal.label>네안데르탈인</Neanderthal.label>
  <Neanderthal.description>Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. Their most salient characteristic is that they are difficult to hurt: They are very resistant to injury, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, without ever having evolved in a complex civilization, they are less adept than baseliner humans at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis was originally an archaic population of hominids that emerged over 200,000 years ago during the Pleistocene epoch. After they were replaced by and merged with humans 30,000 years ago, they were absent for tens of thousands of years until scientists resurrected them from ancient DNA. Neanderthals now survive in sub-societies on some settled planets. On the rimworlds, neanderthal tribes carve out the same existence as their Earth ancestors did so long ago.</Neanderthal.description>
  <Neanderthal.descriptionShort>네안데르탈인은 땅딸막하고 강력하게 만들어진 인종입니다. 그들은 강건하고 튼튼한 신체를 가지고 있으며, 강력한 면역력이 감염으로부터 그들을 지켜줍니다. 그러나 이들의 정신은 지적 및 사회적 작업에 덜 능숙하며, 강한 충동성때문에 위험할 정도로 공격적입니다.</Neanderthal.descriptionShort>
  
  <Pigskin.label>돼지 가죽</Pigskin.label>
  <Pigskin.description>Pigskins are human-pig hybrids which are capable of two-legged movement, tool use, and speech, but which also retain many pig-like qualities. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands leave them at a disadvantage when attempting to precisely manipulate tools and objects. They don't see well at a distance, so pigskin gangs usually focus on close-range weapons. They also have a strong taste for explosives.\n\nPigskins were made for their organs. Uncomfortable with the idea of harvesting organs from baseliner humans, a long-gone government merged human DNA into pigs to make the animals produce more easily-transplantable hearts and lungs. They succeeded, but the resulting creatures became more humanlike than anyone anticipated.</Pigskin.description>
  <Pigskin.descriptionShort>피그스킨은 인간과 돼지의 합성체입니다. 그들은 강건하며 탈 없이 거의 모든 음식을 먹을 수 있지만, 돼지의 발에 더 가까운 그들의 손은 정밀조작이 힘듭니다. 그들은 근시안을 가지고 있어, 대부분 근접무기에 초점을 맞춥니다. 또한 그들은 폭발물을 참 좋아합니다.</Pigskin.descriptionShort>
  
  <Sanguophage.label>생귀오파지</Sanguophage.label>
  <Sanguophage.description>Sanguophages are a type of archotech-enhanced xenohuman. Powered by archites, their abilities go far beyond normal genetic enhancements. They are mentally adept and preternaturally beautiful. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. They don't age or die naturally and never suffer from disease or poison. A sanguophage can make a new sanguophage by reimplanting their own xenogerm into a person.\n\nSanguophages must regularly consume hemogen derived from human blood, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light.\n\nThe first sanguophage appeared thousands of years ago when the lord-explorer Varan-Dur sought to control a hyperintelligent archotech and found himself transformed by it instead. Every sanguophage is descended from him. Since then, sanguophages have often been hunted because of their destabilizing power and their need for blood. Since they can pass for baseliners, many live in hiding among typical humans.\n\nTheir numbers are unknown. Some think they are legends or rare irrelevancies. Some believe sanguophages secretly direct entire human civilizations. The stories speak of eternal lords ruling billions from slate-black space stations, or directing blood sacrifices at conferences in the underlayers of the deepest urbworlds.</Sanguophage.description>
  <Sanguophage.descriptionShort>생귀오파지는 초월입자가 피에 흐르는 불로불사의 존재들입니다. 이들은 아름답고 극도로 지능적입니다. 이들은 어떤 부상이던 회복할 수 있고, 병이나 독으로부터 자유롭습니다. 전투시, 날카로운 돌기를 쏘아내며 부상입은 아군을 치료할 수 있습니다. 생귀오파지는 그 댓가로 생존을 위해 사람의 피를 섭취하고 정기적으로 긴 죽음안식을 취해야합니다. 이들은 불에 쉽게 피해를 받으며, 자외선으로 인해 느려집니다.</Sanguophage.descriptionShort>
  
  <Waster.label>웨이스터</Waster.label>
  <Waster.description>Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo.\n\nOriginally engineered to prevent resettlement of post-apocalyptic deathworlds, wasters are living area-denial weapons. Waster pirates armed with toxic weapons are the bane of many frontier peoples, both on the rimworlds and in the depths of the urbworld hyperstructures.</Waster.description>
  <Waster.descriptionShort>웨이스터는 공격적이며 거의 모든 질병과 독성으로부터 면역입니다. 또한 이들은 부작용 없이 웨이크업과 광이풀 추출물을 사용할 수 있습니다. 독성에 적응한 그들의 신진대사로 인해 플레이크나 야요와 같은 광이 추출물을 계속 섭취해야 합니다.</Waster.descriptionShort>
  
  <Yttakin.label>이타킨</Yttakin.label>
  <Yttakin.description>Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments. Yttakin share a psychic connection with the wildlife and can summon animals to their side during battles. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before.\n\nSince they migrated off their icy birthworld of Yttak, Yttakin settlements live on many planets. Their fur, roaring voices, and aversion to urban living sometimes leads naive outsiders to believe they are simple-minded animals. Quick-minded Yttakin are happy to make good use of such wrong beliefs, whether at the negotiating table or on the battlefield.</Yttakin.description>
  <Yttakin.descriptionShort>이타킨은 매우 추운 행성에서 살아남도록 개조된 개척민들의 후손입니다. 그들의 크기와 털은 추운 환경에서도 견디게 하며, 음성과 정신적으로 동물들과 의사소통하는 능력을 가지고 있습니다. 이들은 느리고, 활력이 부족하며, 정확하지도 않지만, 강인한 체력을 가지고 있습니다.</Yttakin.descriptionShort>
</LanguageData>
